▍2026 辛辛那提 WTA1000 第一轮
阿朗戈 6-2 6-2 大威廉姆斯 · 赛后场上采访
That's Emiliana Arango
阿朗戈就这样进了第二轮
into the second round in Cincinnati
在辛辛那提 生涯第一次
for the first time in her career, taking
而她要面对的人
on one of the true greats of the sport.
是这项运动真正的传奇之一
Venus Williams not able to find the kind
大威廉姆斯今天没能打出
of level she'd have liked today, but you
她想要的水平 但你必须
have to give all credit to the Colombian
把功劳全给这位哥伦比亚人
who did exactly what she needed to do.
她把该做的事做得一丝不苟
A real clarity around her game plan
战术非常清晰
and an impressive execution of it.
执行得也非常出色
62 62
六比二 六比二
Emiliana, congratulations.
埃米利亚娜 恭喜你
We are all so curious to know what
我们都特别想知道
that experience was like.
那是一种什么样的体验
She won her first Grand Slam title
她拿下第一个大满贯的时候
a few months before you were born
离你出生还有几个月
in 2000.
那是二〇〇〇年
I mean, so to play a legend like
跟这样一位传奇交手
that has to be pretty special for you.
对你来说一定很特别
Definitely. It felt so surreal like
确实 感觉太不真实了
when the draw came out and I saw it,
签表出来我一看到
I was like, "Oh man.", it's so exciting
就想 天哪 太兴奋了
to get to have this opportunity.
居然有这样的机会
I mean, growing up, I always saw her on TV
我从小就在电视上看她
and now getting to play her is is really crazy.
现在真的跟她打上了 太疯狂了
What were you focusing on?
你今天主要在专注什么
I mean, there's so much to it emotionally,
情绪上要面对的东西很多
but as far as your game,
但就打法而言
you looked so strong out here.
你今天在场上非常强硬
What were you paying the most attention
你的计划里
to in terms of your plan?
最看重的是哪一点
Honestly, my legs.
说实话 是我的腿
I like my coach told me,
我教练跟我说
I do not want to see you moving slow.
我不想看到你移动变慢
The only thing I want is for legs to go
我只要一件事
for your legs to go fast.
就是你的腿快起来
So, I tried to focus as much
所以我尽可能
as I could on that.
把注意力放在这上面
Try to get as many balls back as I could.
尽量多把球救回去
And I I think I did a good job of it.
我觉得这一点我做得不错
We love having you here in Cincinnati.
很高兴你能来辛辛那提
You have such an incredible story.
你的故事很了不起
We know you're a family girl.
我们知道你很看重家人
Your family invested in your career.
你的家人为你的职业投入很多
I mean, and you are here now
而你现在站在这里
so proud playing some of the best tennis
打着生涯最好的网球
of your life.
让人非常自豪
What have you enjoyed here
在辛辛那提 除了网球
in Cincinnati outside of tennis?
还有什么让你觉得开心
Maybe.
随便说说
Definitely the golf.
肯定是高尔夫
I've been well my coach loves the golf
我教练特别喜欢高尔夫
and the tournament does such a great job
赛事这方面做得特别好
of like letting us play
让我们去打
and giving us some clubs
还给我们配了球杆
and so my coach was out there.
我教练就跑去打了
He's like let's go play some golf.
他说 走 打高尔夫去
The thing is he's really good and I
问题是他打得特别好
am not that good so it really pisses me off.
而我不行 所以真的很气人
All right, last quick question for you.
好 最后一个小问题
We love the trademark backwards hat.
我们都喜欢你标志性的反戴帽
What started this tradition?
这个习惯是怎么来的
It's pretty cool.
挺酷的
Honestly, my mom I my when I
说真的 是我妈妈 我小时候
was younger, my hair wouldn't grow
头发长不出来
and I would like always have it down
我总是把头发披着
and I would put on the hat.
然后戴上帽子
But then my coach, which is funny enough,
但我教练 说来也巧
same coach I have here, he was like,
就是我现在这个教练 他说
"Nobody plays like that.
没人这样打球
You got to put your hair up in a bun
你得把头发盘起来
or like in a ponytail.
或者扎个马尾
Do something with your hair." And
总之得弄一下 然后
so my mom was like,
我妈妈就说
"Why don't you braid it?" And
要不给你编个辫子 于是
so she would braid it.
她就给我编了
And then I was like, "Okay, and what
然后我说 好 那我的帽子
do I do with my hat?" And she goes,
怎么办 她说
"Why don't you just put it backwards?" So,
那你就反着戴呗 所以
I mean, I was 10 years old and I've kept it
那年我十岁 一直戴着
since.
再没换过
Now, I don't think I can take it back.
现在我觉得我改不回来了
Come on, everyone.
来 大家一起
Impossible not to love her.
谁能不喜欢她呢
That is Emiliana Arango.
这就是埃米利亚娜·阿朗戈